Guide to the Time Inc. Time Publishing and Business Records 1929-1999 MS 3009-RG 24
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Promotion and Public Affairs Department Records, 1955-1999; 155.1 Linear feet in 156 record cartons, 1 document case, and 2 flat boxes
  - Subseries IV.L. Photographs and Negatives, 1972-1987; 8 Linear feet in 9 record cartons
    Based on similarity in folder labels to dated materials, undated materials are estimated to be from the 1980s.
    Organized alphabetically using groupings that mainly mirror other Public Affairs series.
    - Events: Advertising Women of New York, Inc., circa 1984 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 1-2)
      Includes one event with the New York governor as a possible special guest and one event with a New York City high school performance.
    - Events: Bermuda Trip by Public Affairs, 1980s (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 3)
    - Events: Black Tie Affair with Alexander? Haig, William F.? Buckley and Barbara? Walters, 1980s (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 4-5)
    - Events: Canada or Chicago: Richard B. Thomas Speech, 1980s (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 6)
    - Events: Creative Conference '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 7)
    - Events: Democratic National Convention, 1984 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 8-10)
    - Events: Detroit Auto Show, 1984?-1987 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 11-12)
    - Events: 50th Anniversary, 1972? (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 13)
    - Events: John Anderson, 1984 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 14)
    - Events: Kealy and Winfield, 1980s (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 15)
    - Events: Kiawah Island Sales Meeting with Cheryl Tiegs, 1978 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 16-17)
    - Events: Kiawah Island Sales Meeting with Cheryl Tiegs, 1978 (Offsite-box 3117, Folder 12)
    - Events: Liptons Dinner, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 1)
    - Events: Marines Lunch, 1980s (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 18)
    - Events: Mary Anna Smith's Birthday, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 19)
    - Events: Mayor Ed Koch, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 20)
    - Events: Political Conventions: Democratic, 1984? (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 3)
    - Events: Political Conventions: Republican: Reception at Dallas Museum of Art, 1984 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 22)
    - Events: Promotion Christmas, 1981 (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 21)
    - Events: Real Estate Magazine Launch Party, 1986 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 2)
    - Events: Robert? Kyle Farewell Party, 1980? (Offsite-box 2878, Folder 23)
    - Events: Robert Sweeney in India, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 1)
    - Events: Robert Sweeney 25th Anniversary, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 2)
    - Events: Roizman 70th Birthday, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 3)
    - Events: Sales Conference, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 4)
    - Events: Shirley MacLaine Luncheon, 1984? (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 5)
    - Events: Queen Elizabeth II (cruise ship) Trip, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 6-7)
    - Events: Time Panel at New York Life, 1984 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 8)
    - Events: Time Sales Conference: La Quinta, 1982 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 9-10)
    - Events: University of Wisconsin: Ferraro, Geraldine, 1985? (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 11)
    - Events: Van Gogh Exhibit at Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1984 or 1986 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 12)
    - Events: Unidentified, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 4)
    - Events: Unidentified, undated (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 13)
      Photographs and negatives of an event in an envelope from photographer Eddy van der Veen. Envelope found loose among materials on the advertising project "Power of Print."
    - Exhibitions: Boston City Hall, 1980 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 14)
    - Exhibitions: Time Cover Art Show: General, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 15)
    - Exhibitions: Time Cover Art Show: Boston Harvard Club, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 16-17)
    - Exhibitions: Time Cover Art Show: Chicago, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 18)
    - Invitational: Maidstone Tournament, 1980s (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 19)
      The Time Inc. Invitational was an annual invitation-only sports competition event organized by the magazines' Advertising Sales Departments and held at the Maidstone Club in East Hamptons, NY from at least 1983 to 1989.
    - Newstours: General: Master Draft for Printed Books, 1986 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 20)
    - Newstours: General: Reprints? from Prior Newstours, 1985 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 21)
    - Newstours: Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 2879, Folder 22-23)
    - Newstours: Time Mid East Newstour, 1975 (Offsite-box 2880, Folder 1-6)
    - Newstours: Time/Update on America '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 2880, Folder 7)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 2880, Folder 8-12)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 2881, Folder 1-4)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour of Africa/Mid East, 1978 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 5)
    - Newstours: Washington Update, 1980 (Offsite-box 2881, Folder 5-6)
      There are no accompanying papers for a 1980 newstour. Notes on these photographs reference the Middle East so these files could relate to either the 1978 or the 1981 newstour or be part of a separate event held in 1980. Notes in the photograph folder for Time/Canada Update on America '85 also call it a "Washington Update."
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 2881, Folder 7-15)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '81: Middle East, Eastern Europe, and Soviet Union, 1981 (Offsite-box 2882, Folder 1)
    - Newstours: Time/Update on America '81, 1981 (Offsite-box 2882, Folder 2)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 6)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '83: Mexico, 1983 (Offsite-box 3040, Folder 4)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '83: Mexico: Panama, 1983 (Offsite-box 2882, Folder 3)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 2882, Folder 4-16)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 1-5)
    - Newstours: Time Newstour '85: Pacific Rim, 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 7-14)
    - Newstours: Time/Canada Update on America '85, 1985 (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 6-14)
    - Newstours: Time/Canada Update on America '85, 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 15-16)
    - Project Files: Distinguished Speakers Program: Mulroney, Brian, 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 17-19)
    - Outside Images: National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA): Space Shuttle, 1981 (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 15)
    - Staff: In Animal Noses Possibly at a Political Convention, 1985? (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 16)
    - Staff: Kennerly, David, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 20)
    - Staff: Kyle, Robert; Megan, Nancy Hall; Ruta, Tony; Sweeney, Robert, undated (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 17)
    - Staff: Levin, Gerald; Kapner, Stan; Oshazak, ______, undated (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 18)
    - Staff?: Meier, Erwin, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 21)
    - Staff: People Magazine, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 22)
    - Staff: Sweeney, Robert; Thomas, Richard, 1984 (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 19)
    - Staff: Slides of Sweeney, Robert; The Wrights, 1985 (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 20)
    - Staff?: Time-Life News Service, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 3261, Folder 23)
  - Subseries IV.M. Press Clippings, Kits, and Releases, 1990-1991; 3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    Materials include cover advisories, full issues, removed covers or copies of the referenced articles, clippings, press kits, and press releases about upcoming Time articles or Time covers. The majority of materials are clippings and releases. Some issues have more than one press release. This run of files that includes press releases appear to be collected separately from the series Press Releases and contains additional materials.
    Organized chronologically by magazine issue date.
    - Press Clippings, Kits, and Releases, 1990 October-1991 January (Offsite-box 2875)
    - Press Clippings, Kits, and Releases, 1991 January-August (Offsite-box 2876)
    - Press Clippings, Kits, and Releases, 1991 September-December (Offsite-box 2877)
  - Subseries IV.N. Press Releases, 1979-1988; 15 Linear feet in 15 record cartons
    The Press Release materials contain official press releases regarding published Time articles, on matters of interest at Time magazine, and releases only distributed to European news outlets.
    Press release on published articles summarized upcoming politics and economics articles, including excerpts from interviews with notable subjects Henry Kissinger and Jimmy Carter. There is also a section of summaries called Time Top Stories. The topics of these press releases are American-centric. Press releases are foldered by individual article title and sometimes have the full article text attached. The years 1983 and 1985 for press releases about articles are not present.
    Press Releases on Time include biographies for Time-Life editors and correspondents, staffing changes, introduction of new sections, circulation increases, and information on special advertising campaigns. The files include some memoranda to Time staff and some press clippings on Time's 60th anniversary. Examples of announcements include being the first American newsmagazine to circulate in China as of August 1979, and the introduction of the Video and Design section in 1981 and the Computer section in 1982. Biographies include a short background and photograph of several Time-Life editors or correspondents, notably Stanley Cloud and James Atwater.
    Press release for other countries contain releases for foreign editions of Time or news outlets outside of the United States including in Asia, Europe, the Middle East, and the Soviet Union.
    This run of files appears to be collected separately from the series Press Clippings, Kits, and Releases.
    Press Releases are organized in three alphabetical groups. General press release folders in the groups Press Releases on Articles and Press Releases on Time are arranged chronologically by year, month, and day with additional titles in alphabetical order after the general folders.
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1978 April-December (Offsite-box 3092)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1979 January-September (Offsite-box 2831, Folder 1-74)
      Includes the September 9, 1979 press release, "Time Editor, James G. Grant, Dies of Heart Attack".
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1979 September-December (Offsite-box 2833, Folder 1-31)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1980 January-April (Offsite-box 2833, Folder 32-66)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1980 April-October (Offsite-box 2834, Folder 1-65)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1980 November-December (Offsite-box 2835, Folder 1-20)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1981 January-April (Offsite-box 2835, Folder 21-62)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1981 April-September (Offsite-box 2836, Folder 1-68)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1982 September-December (Offsite-box 2837, Folder 1-42)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1982 January-February (Offsite-box 2837, Folder 43-57)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1982 February-July (Offsite-box 2838, Folder 1-61)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1982 July-November (Offsite-box 2839, Folder 1-55)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1982 November-December (Offsite-box 2840, Folder 1-22)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1983 January-October (Offsite-box 3262)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1983 November-December (Offsite-box 3263, Folder 1-24)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1984 January-May (Offsite-box 2840, Folder 23-101)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1984 June-December (Offsite-box 2841, Folder 1-50)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1986 January-July (Offsite-box 3263, Folder 25-27)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1986 August-November (Offsite-box 2841, Folder 51-52)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1987 January-March (Offsite-box 3263, Folder 28-29)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1987 April-December (Offsite-box 2841, Folder 53-58)
    - Press Releases on Articles, 1987 January-December (Offsite-box 2842, Folder 1-9)
    - Press Releases on Articles: Time Top Stories, 1976-1984 (Offsite-box 3093, Folder 110-114)
    - Press Releases for Other Countries, 1979-1984 (Offsite-box 3093, Folder 115)
    - Press Releases for Other Countries, 1980-1981 (Offsite-box 2842, Folder 11-12)
    - Press Releases on Time, 1979 February-February 1984 (Offsite-box 3093, Folder 1-107)
    - Press Releases on Time: Biographies, 1977-1984 (Offsite-box 2842, Folder 10)
    - Press Releases on Time: Photo Releases, circa 1984 (Offsite-box 3093, Folder 108)
    - Press Releases on Time: Special Releases, 1978-1981 (Offsite-box 3093, Folder 109)
  - Subseries IV.O. Project Files, 1965-1986; 6 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
    Contain files on projects either created by Time Public Affairs and Promotion (films), wider projects participated in by Time Inc. and overseen by Time Public Affairs and Promotion (Distinguished Speakers Program and Time-Life Academy of Transition), and events organized by Time Public Affairs and Promotion related to Time magazine projects (Power of Print). Further records on a later revival of Power of Print are in Promotion Manager Nancy Hall Megan Files.
    - College Advertising Free Space Program: Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Offsite-box 3117, Folder 1-3)
    - Distinguished Speakers Program, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 3059)
      The Distinguished Speakers Program commenced in 1984 with President Ronald Reagan speaking at his alma mater Eureka College in Illinois. The program was created by Time Public Affairs to celebrate Time's 60th anniversary, and funded by Corporate Public Affairs. It was "intended to bring to campuses throughout the United States a variety of newsmakers who have appeared on the cover of TIME." Other speakers represented include Philippines president Corazon Aquino at New York University, Congress representative and vice president candidate Geraldine Ferraro at the University of Wisconsin/Madison, and Canada prime minister Brian Mulroney at the University of Chicago.
      The Distinguished Speakers Program files are from Public Affairs Coordinator Jean "Nini" Gussenhoven for the 1984 inception lecture, and Special Events Manager Rita Robinson for the continuation through 1986. These files were housed together by the Time Inc. Archives so are kept together here instead of separating them by the file owner's job title.
    - Distinguished Speakers Program, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 3060, Folder 1-12)
      2 videocassettes (VHS) (60 min.): 1/2 in. On container label: "TIME Distinguished Speaker Program. President, Republic of the Phillappines Corazon Aquino. September 19, 1986. A Reeves Corporate Services Production."
    - Distinguished Speakers Program [RESTRICTED], 1984-1986 (Offsite-box R56)
    - Films: The Joy of Knowing: Proposal, 1965 (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 21)
    - Films: Since Time Began, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 2883, Folder 22-24)
      In the invitation for a private showing at Radio City Music Hall, the film Since Time Began is described as "a nostalgic review of the role of newspapers, magazines, radio, film and television since the early 1920's when TIME first set out to record the news of the week." Various promotion staff served as the film crew including assistant to promotion director Alan Martin as the film's director and producer. Prints of the film were sent out on request for viewing in places such as universities by journalism or media classes and companies to show to their sales teams. Time received requests to show up through 1980. Records include the first draft titled Time To Know, bills, scripts, invitations, and showing lists.
    - Films: Since Time Began, 1969-1980 (Offsite-box 2884, Folder 1-16)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Movie. Since Time Began. Music. Webb/Hoernle Inc. 30 East 60 Street, New York 10022. 832-2264."
    - Films: Since Time Began [RESTRICTED], 1969 (Offsite-box R56)
    - John Scott Report on the Pacific Basin, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3117, Folder 4-6)
    - Newsmakers of Tomorrow: Seattle, 1978 (Offsite-box 3117, Folder 7-9)
    - Newsmakers of Tomorrow: Tacoma, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3117, Folder 10-11)
    - New York Urban League: Time-Life Academy of Transition, 1968-1977 (Offsite-box 3012, Folder 1-10)
      The Time-Life Academy of Transition opened in September 1968 in central Harlem. It was part of a New York Urban League initiative called Street Academies to help students complete high school.
      The files are from Public Affairs Director Robert Sweeney; Public Affairs staff and designated liaison to the Urban League Ray Godfrey; and Public Affairs staff Ernest Hill and Jim Roy.
    - New York Urban League: Time-Life Academy of Transition [RESTRICTED], 1970 (Offsite-box R56)
    - Power of Print: Dinner, 1970-1977 (Offsite-box 2884, Folder 17-22)
      According to Henry "Hank" Luce III's speech at the dinner, the "Power of Print" project began in 1969 when Time explored offering free space to advertising agencies to see what they would do with it. The initial proposal was to run 50 submissions. He states that the project became "a vehicle of public service" as agencies ran ads such as a call to "Save our Planet" and a tearsheet questionnaire that could be mailed to the White House. During his speech, Luce announced that the project would be extended.
    - Power of Print: Exhibit: Environment for Response, 1970 (Offsite-box 2884, Folder 23)
    - Power of Print: Printing Industries of Metropolitan New York (PIMNY) Citation, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 2884, Folder 24)
    - Time Index Redesign, 1968 (Offsite-box 2884, Folder 25)
  - Subseries IV.P. Promotion Realia, 1989; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Promotion Realia contains eight box packages of an audio cassette and poster related to the Rolling Stones tour created by Time Promotion. According to former Time Promotion staff, the Rolling Stones mailing was sent to selected advertisers and friends of Time. Sales people would also hand out the package while on sales calls.
    Hooper, Bill. Email to Holly Deakyne, 14 January 2019.
    Materials remain in the original boxes. All boxes are identical.
    - Rolling Stones, Steel Wheels, 1989 (Offsite-box 3011)
  - Subseries IV.Q. General Office Files, 1963-1991; 1.5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    The General Files include files found mixed together either with no known creator or including materials from several people within Time Public Affairs. The chronological groups of files were originally in two groups. The first group includes records from Public Affairs director Robert "Bob" Sweeney; associate director Stan Kapner; publicity manager John "Jack" Mulligan; and public affairs, publicity, and promotion staff Elizabeth Jones, Nancy Hall (later Nancy Megan), and Kerry Arnold. While it has some materials from earlier dates, it looks like the files were created between 1967 and 1970.
    The second group dates from 1990 to 1991 and includes records from Public Affairs director Anne Janas; Communications director Jennifer Epstein; and Public Affairs coordinator Pat Donham Hodges. It isn't clear if or how Public Affairs and Communications were connected, if they were under the same departmental umbrella, but Janas, Epstein and Hodges were working together on the Environmental Challege exhibit and fund. Hodges signs off at different times both as part of Public Affairs and Communications.
    Additional general Public Affairs files found not related to any other files are added after the two chronological groups.
    Organized into two chronological groups, alphabetically within the groups, then alphabetically for additional materials.
    - 1967-1970: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 1-3)
    - 1967-1970: China Institute, 1969 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 4)
    - 1967-1970: Coffey, Richard: Presentation and Advertising Lunch, 1969 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 5)
    - 1967-1970: College Eduacation, 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 6)
    - 1967-1970: Lists: Staff (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 7-9)
    - 1967-1970: Luce, Henry III, 1969 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 10)
    - 1967-1970: The March of Time Film Festival, 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 11)
    - 1967-1970: Shepley, James: Lunch, 1969 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 12)
    - 1967-1970: "Thinking Man's Medium", Saturday Review by Roy Larsen (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 13)
    - 1967-1970: Time Current Events Test, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 14)
    - 1967-1970: Urban Affairs, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 15)
    - 1990-1991: Environmental Challenge (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 16-19)
    - 1990-1991: Environmental Challenge [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R56)
    - 1990-1991: Man of the Year (Offsite-box 2850, Folder 20)
    - Advertising Marketing Public Affairs and Sales Staff Booklet, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 2852, Folder 1)
    - Advertising Promotion Booklet: Want to See Some Great Color?, 1965? (Offsite-box 2852, Folder 2)
    - 1990 Time Publicity Review (Offsite-box 3263, Folder 30-34)
- Series V. Advertising Sales Department Records, 1927-1974; 3.5 Linear feet in 4 record cartons including 21 reels of microfilm
  The Advertising Sales Department Records include files from the offices of the assistant directors, and microfilm of advertiser record cards listing information regarding ads place in Time.
  Subseries V.A. Assistant Director Files
  Subseries V.B. Advertiser Record Cards
  - Subseries V.A. Assistant Director Files, 1963-1974; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    This series contains files from Assistant Advertising Sales Directors Dean Hill and Edmund Burke primarily regarding annual meetings and conferences organized for sales staff. Records include correspondence to and from vendors and venue providers, internal memoranda planning the events, venue brochures, meeting itineraries, general information handouts for participants, itemizations of costs, and participant lists.
    - 40th Anniversary Lists, 1963 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 1-2)
    - Managers Meeting, 1968 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 3)
    - Managers Meeting, 1969 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 4)
    - Managers Meeting, 1970 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 5)
    - Managers Meeting, 1972 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 6-7)
    - Managers Meeting, 1974 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 8)
    - Sales Meetings: Sports Illustrated-Others: Collected Travel Brochures, 1974 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 9-10)
    - Supervisors Meeting, 1970 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 11)
    - Time in New York, 1965 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 12)
    - Time Sales-Marketing Convention, 1974 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 13)
    - Time Sales Meeting, 1966 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 14)
    - Time Sales Meeting, 1969 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 15)
    - Time Sales Meeting, 1969 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 16-18)
      Includes as an event the first Time Worldwide Challenge Cup Golf Tournament.
    - Time Sales Meeting, 1972 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 19-20)
    - Time Sales Meeting: Innisbrook, 1974 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 21-22)
    - Time Sales Meeting: Puerto Rico, 1974 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 23-24)
    - Time Sales and Supervisors Meeting, 1973 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 25)
    - Time Worldwide Challenge Cup Golf Tournament, 1969 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 26)
    - Time Worldwide Challenge Cup Golf Tournament, 1970 (Offsite-box 3265, Folder 27-28)
  - Subseries V.B. Advertiser Record Cards, 1927-1974; 2.5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons including 21 reels of microfilm
    The Time Advertiser Record Cards include microform and physical cards. The majority of the records are on microfilm. The dates refer to the original material and not the creation of the microfilm.